ALEX LING

EMAIL aswling@nyu.edu PHONE (908) 399-5353 LOCATION NYC//NJ

EDUCATION

09/2014 - 05/2018 New York, NY NEW YORK UNIVERSITY (3.8/4.0)
Gallatin School of Individualized Study

Individualized Major: "Visual Storytelling and

Deconstructing Narratives"
Minor: Business of Entertainment, Media, and

Technology (Stern School of Business)

Design I & II // Contemporary Visual Culture and the Politics of Images // Entertainment & Media Industries // Media,

Technology, and Society // How Art Works

Founder and President of Gallazine

Emerging Leader Award Dean's List

08/2016 - 12/2016 Shanghai, China NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SHANGHAI (4.0/4.0)

Study Abroad: General Curriculum, Interactive Media Arts

COURSES

COURSES

ACTIVITIES

Communications Lab // Projects in Western and Chinese

Methods of Art // Chinese II

09/2011 - 06/2014 Princeton, NJ PRINCETON DAY SCHOOL

High School

EXPERIENCE

01/2017 - Present New York, NY AMINO APPS // Design Intern

// Design and illustrate community app icons, feature graphics, and iOS and Android screenshots for App Store and Google Play Store

// Design ad campaigns, make animated graphics for social media, mockup designs for mobile UI // Reach out to artists to feature fanart on Amino

02/2016 - 06/2016 New York, NY **VISIT.ORG** // Visual Editor Intern

// Curate, edit, and upload images to WordPress for organization pages

// Optimize and organize image archive and design presentations

09/2015 - 11/2015 New York, NY THE HOLE // Gallery and Operations Intern

// Open and close gallery, greet visitors, answer questions about exhibitions, install and deinstall exhibitions, art handling, design exhibit postcards

02/2015 - 06/2015 New York, NY SCHOLASTIC // Art Dept Admin Assistant

// Invoice and record-keeping, contract editing, sample warehouse ordering

// Image and photo research, file conversion, assemble prototype products, create "child-like" drawings and handwriting for products

07/2013 - 08/2013 New York, NY THE MET // Education and Digital Media Intern

// Edit thumbnail images for new audio guides // Verify, organize, and tabulate content from 10+ audio guides with 100+ audio guide tour stops // Create and lead group gallery tour and discussion

PROFILE

Hi! I'm Alex. I'm currently a junior at NYU's Gallatin School of Individualized Study where I'm pursuing an individualized major in "Visual Storytelling and Deconstructing Narratives." My major centers around design, art history, and marketing, specifically the ways to best visually communicate ideas and narratives. Outside of school, I have professional experience in design, visual editing, curation, and making creative content. In my free time, I'm usually found doodling in my sketchbook, drawing comics, and working on my UI/UX skills.

WEBSITE aswling.com
LINKEDIN /alexandraling
TUMBLR @alexswling
GITHUB /aswling
INSTAGRAM @aswling

SKILLS

Photoshop
Illustrator
InDesign
Premiere
Audacity
HTML/CSS
JavaScript
InVision
Photography
PaintTool SAI

INTERESTS

Making comics
Making GIFs
Drawing and painting
Museum-hopping
B-films
Cool socks
Dogspotting